Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, 1931-1964
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mann, Thomas, 1937; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Mrs. Sidney Robertson Crowell and played on the dulcimer by Thomas Mann at Ortonville, Iowa, 1937: Haste to the wedding, off she goes (medley) -- Irish washerwoman -- Pigtown fling -- Devil's dream -- Nancy's fancy --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.228
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1936-1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Played by Enos Cansy on the fiddle, Tim Cansy on the mandolin, and Lola Cansy on the guitar at Magee, Miss., 1939: Old blue sow...Recorded by Herbert Halpert and sung with fiddle by Eno Cansy with beating of straws by Jim F. Myers at Magee, Miss., 1939: Where'd you get yo' whiskey? -- Pore little Mary settin' in the corner -- Recorded by Alan Lomax and Elizabeth Lomax and played on the banjo by Justin Bigley of Hazard, KY., 1937: Sally Goodin...Recorded by Fletcher Collins and sung with banjo by O.L. Coffey of Scheull's Mills, N.C., 1936: Oh, fly around, my pretty little miss...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.229
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1941-1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and John W. Work and played by Nashville Washboard Band at Nashville, Tenn., 1941: Soldiers joy...Recorded by Alan Lennox and played by E.C. Ball and Vlair C. Reedy at Rugby, Va., 1941: Bile dem cabbage down...Recorded by John A. Lomax and played by string band with Oscar Harper; Harman Uem; Homer Peters; Ray Hanby with calling by Bob McClary at Dallas Square Dance Club, Dallas, Tex., 1942: The Girl I left behind me -- Sally Goodin --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.230
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1937; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax...Played by string band: J.C. Fowler, Elie Buckner and Alva Ruffner, with calling by S.C. Simon at Lubbock, Texas, 1937: Devil's Dream -- Mississippi Sawyer --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.231
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Boon, Eva Grace and Anne Williams, 1937; 1939; 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song.Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Eva Grace Boone and group at Brandon, Miss., 1937: We're goin' around the mountain...Recorded by Herbert Halpert and sung by Eva Grace Boone and goup at Brandon, Miss., 1939: Old lady sittin' in the dining room -- Little Sally Walker -- All around the Maypole...Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Eva Grace Boone and group at Brandon, Miss., 1937: Sissy in the barn -- Little Rosa Lee...Recorded at Moorehead Plantation, Lula, Miss., 1942, by Alan Lomax and Lewis Jones and sung by Anne Williams and group of Dundee, Miss.: Gwan roun', Rabbit -- Satisfied --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.232
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Stothers, Jimmie and Joe Lee, 1936; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and Harold Spivacke...Sung with guitar by Jimmie Stothers and Joe Lee at State Farm, Virginia, 1936: Do, Lord, remember me -- Sung by Joe Lee at State Farm, Virginia, 1936: House done built without hands -- Oh, the Lamb of God, the Lord done sanctified me -- Sung with guitar by Jimmie Strothers at State Farm, Virginia, 1936: We are almost down to the shore -- Sung by Joe Lee at State Farm, Virginia, 1936: Shines like a star in the morning --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.233
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Reed, Dock, Bosie Sturdivant, and Vera Hall, 1940; 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Dock Reed at Livingston, Alabama, 1940: Down on me -- Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Dock Reed and Vera Hall at Livingston, Alabama, 1940: Certainly, Lord -- Recorded by Alan Lomax and Lewis Jones and sung by Bozie (Bosie) Sturdivant at Silent Grove Baptist Church, Clarksdale, Mississippi, 1942: Ain't no grave can hold my body down --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.234
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Griffin, Sin-Killer, 1934; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax...Spoken by Sin-Killer Griffin with congregational responses and singing at Darrington State Farm, Sandy Point, Texas, 1934: The Man of Calvary (Easter Day services) -- Wasn't that a mighty storm --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.235
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pace, Kelley, 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Kelley Pace and group at Cumins State Farm, Gould, Arkansas, 1942: Holy Babe, part 1 -- Holy Babe, part 2 --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.236
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Johnson, Turner Junior, 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and Lewis Jones...Sung with harmonica by Turner Junior Johnson at Clarksdale, Mississippi, 1942: Meet me in Jerusalem -- When I lay my burden down -- In New Jerusalem -- Steal away --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.237
- Music of the world's people, Vol. IV, 1958; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Complied and edited by Henry Cowell... Ituri forest pygmies -- Borneo (Gamelon) -- Switzerland -- Mexico (Yaqui dance) -- U.S.S.R. (Folk song) -- Estonia -- Rumania (Dance) -- Ceylon -- Austria --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.261
- Music of the world's people, Vol. IV, 1958; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Complied and edited by Henry Cowell... Samoa -- Bretagne -- Portugal (Christmas song) -- Venezuela (Dance) -- Armenia (Dance) -- Sweden (Walking tune) -- Java (Classical song) -- Korea (Classical song) -- Kurdistan -- U.S.A. --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.262
- Negro prison camp worksongs, 1956; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded by Toshi & Peter Seeger, John Lomax, Jr., Chester Bower and Fred Hellerman at Ramsey and Retrieve State Farms, Texas... Let your hammer ring -- Here, rattler, here -- Chopping in the new ground -- Mighty bright light -- Go down old Hannah -- Grizzly bear -- Lost John -- You got to hurry -- I need more power -- We need another witness --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.263
- Old harp singing, Old Harp Singers of Eastern Tennessee, 1951; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Sung by the Old Harp Singers of Eastern Tennessee: Ocean No. 159 -- Greenfields No. 16 -- Hightower No. 87 -- Pleasant Hill No. 43 -- Amazing grace -- Western Mount Pleasant No. 206 -- Wondrous love No. 143 -- Morning trumpet No. 99 -- Northfield No. 115 -- Liberty No. 98 --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.264
- Union songs: Talking union, Seeger, Pete and the Almanac Singers, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Sung by Pete Seeger and Chorus: We shall not be moved -- Roll the union on -- Casey Jones -- Miner's lifeguard -- Solidarity forever -- Join the union -- Hold the fort... The Almanac Singers: Get thee behind me, Satan -- Union maid -- All I want -- Talking union -- Union train -- Which side --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.265
- Riddle me this: Jean Ritchie and Oscar Brand, Ritchie, Jean and Oscar Brand, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions Inc. Sung by Jean Ritchie and Oscar Brand: The Cambric shirt -- The Deaf woman's courtship -- I will give my love an apple -- Marching across the green grass -- Riddle me this -- What are little boys made of -- Madam, will you walk -- Big, glass doll -- Soldier, soldier -- My good old man -- Jennie Jenkins -- The Riddle song -- Paper of pins -- Pretty li'l reckless boy -- Who killed Cock Robin -- Billy Boy --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.266
- Robin Hood ballads, House, Wallace, 1953; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Sung by Wallace House: Robin Hood's Morris -- Robin Hood and the three squires -- The Jolly Pinder of Wakefield -- Robin Hood and the ranger -- Robin Hood's death and burial -- True tale of Robin Hood -- Robin Hood and Little John -- Robin Hood and the Curtall fryer -- Robin Hood and the tanner -- Robin Hood and Maid Marian --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.267 (10in.)
- Songs of the sea, Mills, Alan and the Four Shipmates, 1957; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Sung by Alan Mills and the Four Shipmates with guitar accompaniment by B. Lacombe: Blow boys blow -- Blow the man down -- Clear the track -- Can't you dance the polka -- A Long time ago -- New Bedford whalers -- Fire down below -- The Sailor's grave -- Boney was a warrior -- Santy Anna -- The Chesapeake and Shannon -- Home, Dearie, home -- Goodbye, fare ye well -- Hilo somebody -- Galloping pandy dandy o -- Leave her, Johnny -- Rio Grande -- Haul away Joe -- Sally Brown -- Chee'ly men -- Johnny Boker -- Paddy Doyle -- Dead horse -- Salt horse -- A-roving -- Tom's gone to Hilo -- Ten thousand miles away -- Shenandoah -- Billy Boy -- Lowlands -- Drunken sailor --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.268
- Spanish and Mexican folk music of New Mexico, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded by J.D. Robb in New Mexico and sung by James Trujillo and Sam and Modesto Garcia: Matachines dances -- Sung by Garcilian Pacheco: Huapango -- Sung by Felix Ortega: Entriega de novios -- [Sung by] Librado Leyba and Eddie Ortiz: Polka -- Sung by Alfred Campos and Edwin Lobato: La Luna se va me tiendo -- Cuarto caminos -- Sung by Arthur L. Campa: El Zapatero -- Sung by Daniel Lopez: Grasshopper waltz --Sung by Jacobo Maestas: Cancion ingles -- Sung by congregation: Hymn of farewell -- Sung by Felix Ortega and Consuelo Ortega: Corrida de Elena -- Sung by Vidal Valdez and Lupe Rodriguez: Para queme sirvo el vino -- Sung by: Arvino Martinez: Trovo del viego vilmas -- [Sung by] Jacobo Maestras and Victor Frescas: Cuna --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.269
- Hudde Ledbetter Memorial, Leadbelly, Woody Guthrie, Cisco Houston, Oleander Quartet, Anne Graham, and Sonny Terry, 1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recording supervisor Moses Asch... Reels and blues: Green corn -- Yellow gal -- You can't lose me cholly -- Laura -- Good morning blues -- Leaving blues -- Big fat woman -- Work songs and spirituals: Gray goose -- Pick a bale of cotton -- Take this hammer -- Bring me a little water, Silvy -- Moaning -- Meeting at the building -- We shall walk through the valley -- Irene --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.270 (10in.)
- Songs of the Mormon pioneers, Sorrels, Rosalie, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Festival Records. Rosalie Sorrels sings songs of the Mormon pioneers with the Singing Saints: None can preach the gospel like the Mormons do -- The Gospel news -- Poor wayfaring man of grief -- Tittery-irie-ay -- On the road to California -- The Lonesome roving wolves -- The Dying Californian -- The Handcart song -- The Unknown grave -- Whoa! Haw! Buck and Jerry boy -- Hard time's come again no more -- Don't you marry the Mormon boys -- Blue Mountain -- Once I lived in Cottonwood -- Seagulls and crickets -- Zack, the Mormon engineer -- Echo Canyon -- St. George and the drag-on -- Mormon Yankee Doodle --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.272
- Spirituals with Dock Reed and Vera Hall, Reed, Dock and Vera Hall, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Spirituals with Dock Reed and Vera Hall, and recorded in Alabama by Harold Courlander and assisted by Ruby Pickens Tartt & Emma Courlander: I'm going home on the morning train -- My God ain't no lying man -- Where the sun will never go down -- Troubled Lord I'm troubled -- Look how they done my Lord -- Job Job -- What month was Jesus born in -- Somebody's talking about Jesus -- Death is awful -- I'm climbing up the hills of Mt. Zion -- Low down the chariot and let me ride --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.273 (10in.)
- 900 miles and other R.R. songs, Houston, Cisco, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded by Moses Asch... Sung by Cisco Houston with guitar: The Brave engineer -- The Gambler -- The Rambler -- R.R. Bill -- Worried man blues -- 900 miles -- 'Gettin Up' holler -- The Roamer -- Wreck of the '97 -- Hobo Bill -- The Great American bum --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.274 (10in.)
- Skiffle bands, The Mobile Strugglers, Virgil Perkins, The Memphis Jug Band and Gus Cannon, 1957; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded by Samuel B. Charters... The Mobile Strugglers recorded July 18, 1954, Mobile, Ala....Musicians include: Tyler Jackson, washtub bass; Moochie Reeves, guitar; Ollie Crenshaw, kazoo and guitar: Raise a ruckus tonight -- Rock me, baby -- My bonnie lies over the ocean -- Trouble, trouble followed me all of my days... Interview with Virgil Perkins and songs recorded Nov. 6, 1955, Houston, Texas: Interview -- Goin around the mountain, darlin' Bessie -- John Henry... The Memphis Jug Band with Gus Cannon, and interview with Gus Cannon, recorded December 5, 1956, Memphis, Tennessee... Musicians include: Will Shade, harmonica and guitar; Charlie Burse, tenor guitar; Gus Cannon, 5-string banjo and jug: Harmonica blues -- Tippin' round -- Old John Booker -- Interview -- You call that gone -- Kansas City blues -- Shade and Burse -- Interview -- Take your fingers off it --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.275
- Jack tales, Long, Mrs. Maud Gentry, 1957; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. The Folklore Collection. Recorded at Washington D.C., 1947, by Duncan Emrich... Jack tales told by Mrs. Maud Gentry Long of Hot Springs, North Carolina: Introduction to Jack tales -- Jack and the drill -- Jack and sop dog -- Jack and the bull --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.276
- Song of the Mormons; Songs and ballads of the West, 1938-1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. The Folklore Collection. Songs of the Mormons performed by various people, and recorded in various locations in Utah during the 1940's: On the road to California, or the Buffalo bull fight -- Bull fight -- The Handcart song -- Tittery-ire-aye -- Echo Canyon -- The Utah iron horse -- St. George... Songs and ballads of the West performed by various people, and recorded in various locations in California, Missouri, Arkansas and Arizona in the 1930's and 1940's: Root hog or die -- Starving to death on a government claim -- Joe Bowers -- Custer's last charge -- Sam Bass -- The Brazos River -- Freighting from Wilcox to Globe --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.277
- Singing across the land with Sam Hinton, Hinton, Sam, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Decca Records. The Old-world heritage: Bryan O'lynn -- Our goodman -- The Farmer's curst wife -- Early America: Springfield Mountain -- Johnny Sands -- Jolly Old Roger -- The Greenland fishery -- The Southern mountains: Old Joe Clark -- Ground hog -- Buffalo boy -- The Barnyard song -- The Midwest: Nine hundred miles -- Frankie and Johnny -- Gambler's blues -- The Deep South: Old boastun was dead -- Travelin' man blues -- Tell Old Bill -- The Far West: Echo Canyon -- Doney gal -- Sierra Peaks -- Night herder's song --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.278
- Jazz, Vol. 10: Boogie woogie and jump, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Records from the collection of Frederic Ramsey, Jr.... Boogie woogie: Jim Jackson's jamboree, part I -- Jim Jackson's jamboree, cont'd. -- Hastings Street -- St. Louis blues -- Honky tonk train -- Brown skin gal -- Yancey stomp -- Jump and Kansas City: Let 'em jump -- Toby -- Froggy bottom -- Boogie woogie -- Hootie blues -- Lester leaps in -- Dickie's dream --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.284
- This land is my land: A collection of American folk songs, Guthrie, Woody, Pete Seeger and Leadbelly, 1951; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Sung by Woody Guthrie: This land is my land... Sung by Sam Eskin: Lumbermen's alphabet... Sung by Bill Bonyon: Down the hatch... Sung by Harry McClintock "Mac": Jerry go and oil that car... Sung by Pete Seeger: Young man who wouldn't hoe corn... Sung by Woody Guthrie: Columbia River... Sung by Cisco Houston: Old Blue -- Down in the mines -- Whoopee ti yo yo... Sung by Leadbelly: Old man -- Haul away Joe --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.285 (10in.)
- American industrial ballads, Seeger, Pete, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded by Moses Asch... Sung by Pete Seeger, with 5-string guitar, Songs from 1800 to 1924: Peg and awl -- The Blind fiddler -- Buffalo skinners -- Eight hour day -- Hard times in the mill -- Roll down the line -- Hayseed like me -- The Farmer is the man -- Come all you hardy miners -- He lies in the American land -- Casey Jones -- Let them wear their watches -- Weaver room blues -- Songs from the 1920's to the 1940's: Cotton mill colic -- Cotton and 40c. meat -- Mill mother's lament -- Fare ye well, old Ely Branch -- Beans, bacon and gravy -- The Death of Harry Simms -- Winnsboro cotton mill blues -- Ballad of Barney Graham -- My children are seven in number -- Raggedy, raggedy are we -- Pittsburgh town -- 600/0 parity --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.286
- Negro folk music of Africa and America, 1951; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; [New York, N.Y.], Folkways Records & Serv. Corp. Various African songs performed by various groups: South Africa (Zulu); French Equatorial Africa (Badouma); Nigeria (Yoruba and Ibo); Sudan; Zanzibar (Swahili); Eritrea (Tigrai); Ethiopia (Amhara); SWF PRE1980.1/D.287
- Mexican corridos, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded in Mexico... Corrido de Cananea -- La Rejeca -- El Arreglo religioso -- Toma de gelava -- Andava ausente Simon --Prietita de ojos negros -- La Vaquilla (Corrido de Pancho Villa) -- El Minero --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.288 (10in.)
- Spain: Flamenco music of Anadalusia, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded by Walther Hennig... Flamenco dance song -- Bulerias -- Soleares -- Malaguenas -- Andalusian folk song -- Soleares for guitar -- Cuadro flamenco -- Saeta (Andalusian religious folksong) -- Anadulasian folksong -- Anadulasian folksong -- Song from Malaga -- Malaguenas -- Peteneras -- Rumores de la caleta -- Recuerdos de la Alhambra --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.289
- Folk music of Palestine, 1951; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded by the Anthropological Institute of Israel and produced through the cooperation of the Wenner-Gren Foundation... Songs are Hebrew, Arabic, Bokharian and Persian... Gulait dore -- Al matcha anora -- Tulkum -- Raftam rayi -- Taki chasma -- Recitation from Firdausi's shahname -- Ve eem lo asksahv -- Bible recitation on Sabbath -- Kedusha -- Kether -- Song of Moses -- Ceremonial song -- Prophet's birthday song -- Song of Ramadan -- Recitation from the Koran -- Love song --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.290
- Mariachi aguilas de Chapala, 1960; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Mariachi music from the Mexican state of Jalisco recorded in Chapala, Jalisco, with notes on mariachi music by Charles M. Bogert & Martha R. Bogert... Atotonilco -- Las Olas -- La Negra -- Jarabe Tapatio -- La Bamba -- Chapala -- Tecalitlan -- La Adelita -- Las Bicicletas -- Ojos Tapatios -- Ay, Jalisco no te rajes -- Las Mananitas -- El Carretero se va --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.292
- Two-way trip: American, Scots and English folksongs, Seeger, Peggy and Ewan MacColl, 1961; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Sung by Peggy Seeger and Ewan MacColl: Waly, Waly -- Richie story (Child #232) -- The Crafty farmer (Child #283) -- The Barring of the door (Child #275) -- Jenny Nettles -- Old Lady All Skin and Bones -- Tullochgorum -- The Two brothers (Child #49) -- Just as the time was flowing -- Jackaro -- The Carrion crow -- Matty Groves (Child #81) -- The Bartley explosion -- The Devil's nine questions (Child #1) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.293
- American play-parties, Seeger, Pete, Mika Seeger and Larry Eisenberg, 1959; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Mazoo, mazoo -- Skip to my lou -- Shake them 'simmons down -- Alabama bound -- Sally down the alley -- Turn the glasses over -- Goodbye Liza Jane -- Git along home -- Paw paw patch -- Betty Larkin -- Jolly is the miller -- Pig in the parlor -- Great big house in New Orleans -- Sent my brown jug down town --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.294
- Negro folk music of Africa and America, 1951; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Edited by Harold Courlander... Recorded by Harold Courlander, Ricardo Alegria and Melville J. and Frances S. Herkovits... Songs are from Cuba, Trinidad, United States, Brazil, Colombia, Haiti, and Puerto Rico... Lucumi song -- Shango cult song -- Beli dance -- What shall I do to be saved -- Didn't you hear my Lord when He called -- My name has been written down -- Move members move -- Jesha for Oshun -- Cowherds' festival -- Worksong -- Juba dance -- Nago dance -- Meringue -- Gallinita toma tu maiz --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.295
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Calaveras, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana SA. Performed by Trio Calaveras (Pepe, Raul y Miguel)... Cancion: Palomita (Pedro Galindo), from the film, "Una Cancion en la Noche"... Huapango: Quiereme chiquita (Lorenzo Barcelata) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.296 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hermanos Chavarria, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Columbia. Mexican vocal duo: Hermanos Chavarria, [accompanied by guitars]: Corrido, Los Tequileros, part I and part II (by Jose Garcia) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.297 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Escobarete, Leopoldo y Torres, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Columbia. Performed by vocal duo: Leopoldo Escobarete y Torres, [accompanied by guitars]: Corrido del bajo -- El Pajaro carpintero --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.298 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hernandez, Luis and Leonardo Sifuentes, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Camden, N.J., Victor Talking Machine Co. Performed by Luis Hernandez and Leonardo Sifuentes, [with two guitars]: El Contrabando de El Paso, parts I and II --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.299 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Agustin Irusta y Orquesta Americo Caggiano, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana SA. Performed by Agustin Irusta y Orquesta Americo Caggiano... Tango: Encuentro (Miguel Buoino) -- Cancion: Las Mentiras de Jose (Robledo, Riveroll y Cabral) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.300 (10in.)
- Potpourri de bailes mexicanos; Boogie woogie, Orq[uestra] de Juan S. Garrido, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., Discos Peerless. La Raspa -- Hamp's boogie woogie (Lionel Hampton) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.301 (10in.)